Lav Ranjan Giri

Software Engineer

Phone: +91-8197630451

E-mail: lavranjankumar@gmail.com

Career Objective

To work in a challenging job environment that utilizes my skills and abilities, and offers ample learning opportunities.

Resume Summary

- **2.5** Years of IT experience .
- Expertise in web application development using PHP, Laravel 5+ with relational database like MySQL, MS Sql and Postgres Database.
- Advance knowledge of using client side scripting language like JavaScript,JQuery,Ajax.
- Very good hands on experience with writing Eloquent based query and Raw query.
- Expertise in writing Restful services in laravel with Passport and JWT authentication.
- Expertise in create and maintain Stored Procedure, Trigger, Events in MySQL.
- Very good knowledge of writing web services for Android mobile application in PHP with MS SQL Server and MySQL.
- Expertise in create and maintain User defined function and queries in Postgresql 9.5.
- Very good knowledge of reporting service in MS SQL Server to design and develop different types of SSRS Report and Subreports.
- Very good knowledge of version control system like GIT and SVN.

Experience Summary

- Worked in City-Link Portal Private Limited (Bangalore) as Software Engineer in web application development. (From February 2016 to Sep 2017)
- Worked in Pace wisdom solution Private Limited (Bangalore) as PHP Backend
 Developer in web application development. (From February 2016 to Present)

Technical Skill Set

Internet Technology : HTML, ASP.NET 3.5,4.0, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Ajax

Microsoft Technologies : ADO.NET 3.5,MVC 4,
 Languages : PHP,Laravel,C#.Net

Web & App Server
 IIS 6.0, Wamp, Xampp, Apache

Database : SQL Server 2012, MySQL 5.6, Postgres 9.5

Development Tools : Visual Studio.NET

2015, Sublime, PhpStorm, NetBeans

Operating System : Windows 7/8/10,Ubuntu 16.04

Version Control Systems : Git ,SVN

Educational and Professional Development

Master of computer applications(MCA)

2013-2016

Visvesvaraya Technological University, Belgaum (Karnataka)

Percentage: 78%

Bachelor of computer applications(BCA)

2010-2013

Chaudhary Charan Singh University, Meerut (U.P)

Percentage: 74%

Professional Projects

Project 1: City-Link on Demand Truck Hiring web application (Feb 2016-Jul 2016)

Description:

- Team size 4
- Organization City Link Portal Private Limited (Bangalore).
- Technology used ASP.NET MVC, C#, MS SQL Server

The main objective of this project is automate the truck hiring service in Bangalore for logistics transportation. Register user can visit the website to book the vehicle. They have fill some mandatory detail about the sender, receiver and pickup, drop location. After confirmation of the booking they will get an order number and by that they can track the truck that is assigned for that order.

Role and Responsibilities:

- Involved in Requirement gathering and design document.
- Developed web forms in ASP.NET using C# as the code-behind language and LINQ as the SQL data consumer.
- Used ADO.NET objects such as Dataadapter, Datareader, Dataset and Data List for reading/updating records in the database.
- Developed master pages.
- Involved in creation of stored procedures in MS SQL Server 2008.
- Unit testing module level.

Project 2: City Link- Trucks Contract

(July 2016-April 2017) Description:

- Organization City Link Portal Private Limited (Bangalore)
- Team size 5
- Technology used PHP, Laravel 5+ ,MySQL, JavaScript and JQuery.

This Application facilitates customer to hire trucks on contract basis for their logistics transportation. Customer will be asked to enter mandatory detail into the system to create a contract. Invoice, Trip sheet and other report will be generated by the system on the month basis.

Role and Responsibilities:

- Building PHP websites using Laravel 5.4 frameworks.
- Back end development and maintenance of websites using PHP and MySQL.
- Developing compatible User Interface functionality using JQuery & other libraries.
- Working with a multidisciplinary team to convert business needs into technical specifications.
- Testing and validating work produced as part of the development process.

Project 3: One Payroll web and Mobile application

(OCT 2017 - Present)

Description:

- Team size 4
- Organization Pace wisdom solution Private Limited (Bangalore).
- Technology used Laravel 5.4, Postgres 9.5, JavaScript, Ajax

The main objective of this project is automate payroll system of a organization.

As it's a tenant level database architecture to provide service to multiple tennant.

This application Involves thing like creating employee and setting organization paycycle environment.

Role and Responsibilities:

- Involved in Requirement gathering and design document.
- Involved in creating tenant level Database architecture with mysql.
- Written user defined function to calculate payroll of the employee.
- Used laravel eloquent query for CRUD operation for all the module.
- Unit testing module level.
- Written Restful api for mobile application.

Other Project :

Written Restful API's for:-

OnePayroll Mobile application, Citylink OND android application, Citylink Contract driver application.

Personal Detail

Date Of Birth : July 13,1991Marital Status : Unmarried

Declaration

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my

knowledge.

PLACE: Bangalore LAV RANJAN GIRI